Register of the S. I. Hayakawa papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- San Francisco and Other California District Offices File (Boxes 311-406)
  - San Francisco Office (Box 389)
    - Projects (Box 400)
      - Projects description (Box 404)
      - Health aspects
      - Environmental data
      - Grant offer
      - Eda correspondence
      - Leters of support
    - Robo letters (tapes) (Box 405)
      - Constituency Council
        - 7/23/79
        - 12/19/78
        - Tape 4
        - 7/17/78
        - 5/24/79
        - Tape I
        - 10/5/78
        - 8/9/78
        - 1/15/79
        - Ref
        - Tape II
      - Mini Constituency Council additions, 6/13/79
      - Constituency Council Tape I
      - Constituency Council - Return to Pam, 8/25/78
      - I Belong to Sue
      - Tape No. 91G/V Urban Beautification - Contract and transmittal letter
      - Eagle Scout Award
      - Coop Agreement Resolution for JAK
      - Guest Worker letter (English)
      - Model lease Ref 1-3
      - Labor Relations Staff
      - Page Com. letter
      - Tape No. 6 for use on Tuesday
      - Sm. Chamber
      - D - Tape response letters, 1978
      - Girl Scouts first class award
      - 14 Reuse robo tapes
    - Pictures and certificates
      - City of Industry, plaque, September 17, 1969
      - Rotary Plaque, Westwood Rotary Ashtray, February 16, 1971
      - Carmichael Chamber Plaque, November 25, 1975
      - County of Los Angeles certificates, April 12, 1977
      - Certificate of Commendation, August 15, 1977
      - National Association Physical Therapists Plaque, Seal of California Plaque, January 18, 1981
      - Profession code statistics, July 6, 1981
      - Campaign Poster, 1982
    - Videocassettes (Box 406-406A)
      - S. I. Hayakawa, 7/7/81
      - Opening for Republican Convention
      - KNBC Editorial reply, 7/15/81
      - Blank tape
    - Tape cassettes
      - California Employment Association
      - Scag undocumented issue, Long Beach, (2 tapes), 1/9/82
    - Files on issues SIH took personal interest in
      - Iran
      - Japan
      - Rhodesia
      - English as an official language
      - Bilingual education
      - Immigration
      - US/Mexico border
      - Guest Worker Program
      - Youth Constituency Program
      - Six plaques
      - One Holy Bible
      - One photograph
      - Commendation certificates
- Papers Received From S. I. Hayakawa Residence (Boxes 407-464)
  - Campaign newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box 407-409)
  - Speeches (Box 410-413)
  - Semantics - Institute of General Semantics (Box 414-426)
  - General correspondence, subject file, and writings (Box 427-442)
  - Campaign newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box 443)
  - Clippings, pre-1968 (Box 444-448)
  - Campaign newspaper clippings, 1976 (Box 449-453)
  - Speeches (Box 454-462)
  - Memorabilia - CLOSED (Box 463)
    Access
    Box 463 is closed. Access images are available in Box 462.
  - 1 placard (Box 464)
  - 1 poster
- Incremental Materials (Boxes 465-619)
  Scope and Contents note
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu
- Incremental Sound Recordings (Boxes 620-625)
- 2014 Incremental Materials, 1952-1988 (Boxes 626-636)
  - San Francisco State College records and correspondence, 1952-1982
    Includes clippings, correspondence, institutional records, and memoranda.
    - "Problems in practical communications" conference, 1960 (Box-folder 626: 1)
    - Honolulu Star-Bulletin clipping, 1968 (Box-folder 626: 2)
    - Proposal and notes for book written by Hayakawa regarding the student strike at San Francisco State College, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 626: 3)
    - Flyers, manifestos, and pamphlets denouncing Hayakawa, circa 1970 (Box-folder 626: 4)
    - List of donated books, circa 1970 (Box-folder 626: 5)
    - Black Studies Institute correspondence, 1968-1968 (Box-folder 626: 6)
    - California Supreme Court decision, 1973 (Box-folder 626: 7)
    - Political cartoons, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 626: 8)
    - Classroom invasion notes, circa 1960 (Box-folder 626: 9)
    - Correspondence, San, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 626: 10)
    - School name change clippings, 1973 (Box-folder 626: 11)
    - Dumke, Glenn, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 626: 12)
    - Newspaper clippings regarding Hayakawa, 1952-1972 (Box-folder 626: 13-15)
    - English department materials, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 626: 16)
    - Video lecture contract, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 626: 17)
    - Experimental college materials, 1968 (Box-folder 626: 18)
    - Faculty renaissance, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 626: 19)
    - Fan mail, 1969 (Box-folder 627: 1)
    - Payroll information, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 627: 2)
    - Clippings from and regarding The Daily Gator, San Francisco State University's student newspaper, 1967 (Box-folder 627: 3)
    - John Gerassi clippings, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 627: 4)
    - Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 627: 5)
    - History of San Francisco State College, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 627: 6)
    - Jackson, Charles, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 627: 7-8)
    - Clippings and correspondence regarding an undercover police officer posing as a student, 1973 (Box-folder 627: 9)
    - Job offers, 1969 (Box-folder 627: 10)
    - Legal correspondence and documents, 1974 (Box-folder 627: 11)
    - Correspondence with legislators, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 627: 12)
    - Correspondence from supporters, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 627: 13-14)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1964-1977 (Box-folder 628: 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence within San Francisco State University, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 628: 2)
    - Lexicography, 1969 (Box-folder 628: 3)
    - Magazine articles regarding Black Student Union, 1969 (Box-folder 628: 4)
    - Memorandum and bibliographies regarding Black Student Union, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 628: 5)
    - Department merger, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 628: 6)
    - Invitations, memorandum, proposals, and newsletters, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 628: 7)
    - Press, 1969 (Box-folder 628: 8)
    - Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 628: 9)
    - Clippings regarding San Francisco State University, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 628: 10)
    - Memorandum, 1968 (Box-folder 628: 11)
    - Clippings regarding obscenity, 1967 (Box-folder 628: 12)
    - Memorandum, flyers, and press releases, 1969 (Box-folder 629: 1)
    - Clippings regarding other universities, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 629: 2)
    - The Poetry Center materials, 1969 (Box-folder 629: 3)
    - Peat, Marwick, Mitchell and Co., report on San Francisco State University student strike, 1969 (Box-folder 629: 4)
      Includes DVD of two California Newsreel productions from 1969: "Black Panther" and "San Francisco State: On Strike"
    - Phone record notes, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 629: 5)
    - Policy, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 629: 6)
    - "The College Position on the Strike Demands", 1968 (Box-folder 629: 7)
    - Pronouncements, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 629: 8)
    - Referendum, 1967 (Box-folder 629: 9)
    - Announcements to faculty "On the Record" newsletter, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 629: 10)
    - Assembly Concurrent Resolution Number 2, 1969 (Box-folder 629: 11)
    - Correspondence regarding retirement, 1972 (Box-folder 629: 12-13)
    - Articles regarding retirement, 1972 (Box-folder 629: 14)
    - Student rights and responsibilities, 1969 (Box-folder 629: 15)
    - General Semantics Center, 1969 (Box-folder 629: 16)
    - Scholarship fund, 1968 (Box-folder 630: 1)
    - Security, 1969 (Box-folder 630: 2)
    - Smith, Robert R., 1968 (Box-folder 630: 3)
    - Speech department materials, 1968 (Box-folder 630: 4)
    - Clippings and correspondence regarding students, 1963-1973 (Box-folder 630: 5)
    - Summer session materials, 1951-1959 (Box-folder 630: 6)
    - Summerskill, John, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 630: 7)
    - Off-campus teaching, 1969 (Box-folder 630: 8)
    - Clippings and correspondence regarding violence on universities campuses nationwide., 1969-1973 (Box-folder 630: 9)
    - Today's Health correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 630: 10)
    - Thank you letters, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 630: 11)
    - Faulty work load, 1971 (Box-folder 630: 12)
    - Writings by Hayakawa, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 630: 13)
  - San Francisco State College Class Files, 1960-1988
    Includes files from courses taught by Hayakawa.
    - Art 191, 1966 (Box-folder 630: 14)
    - General semantics seminar, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 630: 15-18)
    - General semantics seminar, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 631: 1-2)
    - English 128, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 631: 3-4)
    - English 228, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 631: 5-6)
    - Education 203.5, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 631: 7)
    - English 6.1, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 631: 8)
    - Publications list, circa 1960 (Box-folder 631: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1984 (Box-folder 631: 10)
    - Greeting cards, 1988 (Box-folder 631: 11)
  - General correspondence, 1952-1988
    Includes correspondence arranged alphabetically.
    - Alvardo, Susan, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 631: 12)
    - American Psychological Association, 1964-1975 (Box-folder 631: 13)
    - Allison, Dr. Gerard F., 1963-1968 (Box-folder 631: 14)
    - Art invoices, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 632: 1)
    - Austin, Claire, 1952-1986 (Box-folder 632: 2)
    - Biography for Hayakawa, 1980 (Box-folder 632: 3)
      Contains curriculum vitae as of 1980
    - Bateson, Gregory, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 632: 4)
    - Bohemian Club, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 632: 5)
    - Car materials, 1971 (Box-folder 632: 6)
    - Civil rights clippings, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 632: 7)
    - Department of Motor Vehicles, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 632: 8)
    - Ekert, Katherine, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 632: 9)
    - Flightapes stock, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 632: 10)
    - Haley, Alex, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 632: 11)
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc., 1988 (Box-folder 632: 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, Henderson-Hyman, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 632: 13)
    - Hoover Institution, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 632: 14)
    - Jolly, Nancy, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 632: 15)
    - Jean, Sidney, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 632: 16)
    - Johnson, Wendell, 1945-1975 (Box-folder 632: 17)
    - Jordan, Phil, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 633: 1)
    - Land reform, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 633: 2)
    - Language in Thought and Action, 1943-1958 (Box-folder 633: 3-4)
    - Lafever, Dr. Ernest, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 633: 5)
    - Lehmann, Harry V., 1973-1983 (Box-folder 633: 6)
    - Lochard, Metz, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 633: 7)
    - Matzen, Richard and Gretchen, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 633: 8)
    - Mckee, Andi, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 633: 9)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1970 (Box-folder 633: 10)
    - Hyde Park, 1963 (Box-folder 633: 11)
    - Revolution, 1965 (Box-folder 633: 12)
    - "The Word 'Negro'", 1968 (Box-folder 633: 13)
    - Huck Finn, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 633: 14)
    - Watts riots, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 634: 1-3)
    - Nugent, John, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 634: 4)
    - Eldridge Cleaver clippings, 1968 (Box-folder 634: 5)
    - Oshima, Kazunori, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 634: 6)
    - Orly, Elvira, 1978 (Box-folder 634: 7)
    - Palumbo, Clara, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 634: 8)
    - Popper, Karl R., 1954-1974 (Box-folder 634: 9)
    - Robbins, Warren, 1975-1989 (Box-folder 634: 10-11)
    - Rosebourgh, Daisy, 1969 (Box-folder 635: 1)
    - Corrigan, Robert A., 1988-1989 (Box-folder 635: 2)
    - Clippings, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 635: 3)
    - San Francisco Chronicle, 1947-1968 (Box-folder 635: 4)
    - San Francisco State University, 1968-1985 (Box-folder 635: 5-8)
    - Inside newsletter, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 635: 9)
    - Self-fulfilling prophesy, 1962-1974 (Box-folder 635: 10)
    - Selye, Hans C. C., 1978-1981 (Box-folder 635: 11)
    - Steiner, Helen, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 635: 12)
    - Stone, W. Clement, 1964-1980 (Box-folder 636: 1)
    - Tanaka, Togo, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 636: 2)
    - Through the Communications Barrier, 1979 (Box-folder 636: 3)
    - Toguri, Iva, 1975-1985 (Box-folder 636: 4)
    - Uono, Issaku, 1969-1983 (Box-folder 636: 5)
    - Vietnam, 1967 (Box-folder 636: 6)
    - Notes from Vietnam trip, undated (Box-folder 636: 7)
    - Walker, Harry, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 636: 8)
    - Wildavsky, Aaron, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 636: 9)
- 2016 Incremental Materials (Boxes 637-641)